<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lab | Rian Rainey]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rian.me/blog/categories/lab/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rian.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-11T11:37:08-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rian.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rian Rainey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waking Up Early]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rian.me/blog/2013/11/11/waking-up-early/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-11T07:58:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rian.me/blog/2013/11/11/waking-up-early</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#39;m giving &quot;Becoming A Morning Person&quot; another chance to be a
habit in my life. I recently read an article on
<a href="http://99u.com/workbook/19887/labrat-become-a-morning-person">99U</a> that
encourgaged readers to wake up early in an effort to be more productive
and happy. I decided to join this movement. I spoke so much about this
that my wife decided to do day 1 with me too. You can follow more of the
movement with the hastag,
<a href="http://twitter.com/#labrat">#labrat</a></p>

<p>Here was my schedule for night/day 1:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>9:30pm</strong> - Start getting ready for bed</li>
<li><strong>9:45pm</strong> - Roughly list items to do at 6am</li>
<li><strong>10:00pm</strong> - Go to sleep</li>
<li><strong>6:00am</strong> - Attempt to wake up. Reset alarm to 6:30am.</li>
<li><strong>6:30am</strong> - Convince my wife to get up with me since she requested that
encouragement.</li>
<li><strong>6:45am</strong> - With coffee in hand, I read my text messages and found my brother
wanted me to listen to his recent podcast episode. So, I derailed once again from my to
do list and listened to the podcast.</li>
<li><strong>7:00am</strong> - Convince my wife to let me go upstairs where I could be alone
to journal for 1/2 hour.</li>
<li><strong>7:15am</strong> - Journaling results in getting motivated to do work. So I stop
journaling early to start coding. My email is open so I&#39;m getting
inundated with auto-generated subscription emails. Responded to a few
emails and then promptly closed it.</li>
<li><strong>7:30am</strong> - Coding results in me debugging my Octopress blog install for
the next 1.5 hours before I really need to start doing some real,
&quot;pay-the-bills&quot;, work.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="toc_0">Takeaways</h2>

<p>I set out to do tons of work in the morning but didn&#39;t get nearly as
much done as I wanted. It was a good start to the &quot;morning person&quot;
routine, I believe. </p>

<p>Things I want to do better tomorrow:</p>

<ul>
<li>Wake up at 6am. No snoozing.</li>
<li>Don&#39;t read email, text messages, Twitter, or Instagram before 9am.</li>
<li>Set out to accomplish only 1 thing in the morning instead of
attempting to do many things.</li>
<li>Keep journaling in my morning routine.</li>
<li>Make sure my wife has tasks to accomplish so I&#39;m free to work :)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
